Finding Aid for Blair Moody Papers 1928-1954
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Blair Moody Papers
1928-1954
1934-1952
Moody, Blair, 1902-1954.
Detroit newspaperman and United States Senator from Michigan. Correspondence chiefly concerning his 1952 senatorial campaign and his newspaper work in the United States and abroad during World War II; scrapbooks of newspaper articles written by Moody and published for the most part in the Detroit News and Barron's; tape recordings of public affairs radio program; photographs and motion pictures of public affairs interview programs.
8634 Aa 2
27.5 linear feet in 29 boxes
29 film reels
60 phonograph records
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Mrs. Blair Moody and Blair Moody, Jr. (donor 3224 ) in 1956.
The collection is open for research.
Arthur Edson Blair Moody was born in New Haven, Connecticut, on February 13, 1902, the son of Arthur Edson Blair and Julia (Downey) Moody. He attended public schools in Providence, Rhode Island, and was graduated from Brown University in 1922, with a B.A. degree in economics. Following graduation from college, he taught and coached for one year at the Moses Brown School in Providence, and in 1923 became an employee of the Detroit News. At first a sportswriter, Moody afterward covered the Detroit City Hall as a reporter during the mayoralty administration of Frank Murphy.
In 1933 Blair Moody became a correspondent in the Washington office of the News, writing the column "The Lowdown on Washington". He also wrote for the Boston Globe, and was correspondent for Barron's from 1934 to 1948 and for the North American Newspaper Alliance since 1936. During World War II Moody served as a war correspondent in North Africa, Italy, Iran, and Britain, and after the war visited the Marshall Plan and North Atlantic Treaty countries to report on economic progress there. Beginning in 1946 he moderated the radio and television program Meet Your Congress, and from 1944 to 1945 he was economic consultant for the Committee for Economic Development.
Appointed to the United States Senate on April 23, 1951, by Michigan's Democratic Governor G. Mennen Williams, Blair Moody filled the vacancy created by the death of Senator Arthur H. Vandenberg on April 18, 1951. The late Senator's term would have ended January 3,1953.
On taking his oath of office the new Senator indicated that in 1952 he would be a candidate for a full six-year term. Stating that he hitherto had not belonged to any party, he said he became a Democrat on the day of his appointment to the Senate by Governor Williams. On becoming a Senator, Moody resigned from the Detroit News, but continued for a time his weekly radio program.
In the Senate Moody was named to the Senate Banking and Currency Committee and the Committee on Expenditures in the Executive Departments, for which he was deemed well suited because of his background in economics. In July 1951, two months after taking office, Moody was named to head the subcommittee of the Senate Small Business Committee, set up to protect the interests of small business in the defense program. He immediately announced that as its first project the subcommittee would study the problem of steel cutbacks in the automobile industry, steel shortages among small businessmen, and unemployment traceable to plant dispersals. On the subject of controls against inflation the Michigan legislator took a firm stand in supporting the Administration's drive to strengthen and extend controls. In August Moody was appointed to a special subcommittee of the Senate Banking Committee, which conducted hearings on a proposal to restore the Government's power to set slaughtering quotas for livestock.
Moody sought election to the Senate in his own right, but was defeated by Charles E. Potter. In 1954 he again sought the Democratic nomination for the Senate seat held by Homer Ferguson. He died unexpectedly while campaigning July 20, 1954.
Blair Moody was the author of a book Boom or Bust (1941), a discussion of the economic aspects of World War II, in which he proposed a constructive program to prevent inflation and postwar economic collapse. Moody was a member of the Gridiron Club, the organization of Washington correspondents. He also belonged to the National Press Club, the Overseas Writers Club, and the University Club in Washington, DC; to the Detroit Club and to the Cammarian Club in Providence, Rhode Island.
Blair Moody on June 6, 1925, married Mary Williamson, by whom he had one son, Arthur Edson Blair, Jr. His two younger sons, Christopher Sorenson and Robert Orten, were born to his second wife, the former Ruth Curtis Amadon, whom he married on September 14,1940.
The Blair Moody collection documents the career of a Washington-based newspaper correspondent and columnist and United States Senator. The collection covers the period 1928 to 1954, though the bulk of materials date since the mid-1940s. Much of the collection pertains to that period of time when Moody was in the Senate or was running for election to the Senate, although his newspaper career is also well documented. The collection has been divided into the following series: Biographical; Correspondence; Personal/Family; Newspaper Career; Gridiron Club; Senatorial Papers; Speeches; Scrapbooks; Sound Recordings; and Visual Materials.
Subjects:
American newspapers--Michigan--Detroit.; Automobile industry and trade--United States.; B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundation (University of Michigan); Democratic Party (Mich.); Depressions--1929--United States.; Detroit (Mich.)--Newspapers.; Detroit (Mich.)--Race relations.; Elections--Michigan--1942.; Journalists--Michigan--Detroit.; Labor unions--Michigan.; McCloy, John J. (John Jay), 1895-1989; Michigan--Politics and government--1929-1938.; Michigan--Politics and government--1939-1945.; Michigan--Politics and government--1946-1960.; Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-; Moody, Blair, 1902-1954.; New Deal, 1933-1939--Michigan.; Politicians--Michigan.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; Saint Lawrence Seaway.; Soviet Union.; Tennessee Valley Authority.; Trucking--United States.; United States. Congress--Elections, 1952.Elections, 1952.; United States. Congress--Elections, 1954.Elections, 1954.; United States. Dept. of State.; United States. Economic Cooperation Administration.; United States--Politics and government--1929-1933.; United States--Politics and government--1933-1945.; United States--Politics and government--1953-1961.; United States--Politics and government--1945-1953.; United States. Temporary National Economic Committee.; World War, 1939-1945.
Contributors - Manuscripts
Acheson, Dean, 1893-1971.; Arnold, Thurman Wesley, 1891-1969.; Ball, Joseph H. (Joseph Hurst), 1905-1993; Barkley, Alben William, 1877-1956.; Baruch, Bernard M. (Bernard Mannes), 1870-1965.; Benton, William, 1900-1973.; Billington, Ray Allen, 1903-1981; Bowles, Chester, 1901-1986.; Boyle, William M.; Brewster, Owen, 1884-; Brown, Prentiss M. (Prentiss Marsh), 1889-1973.; Brownell, Herbert, 1904-1996; Butler, Richard Austen, Baron Butler of Saffron Walden, 1902-1982; Byrnes, James Francis, 1879-1972.; Cain, Harry P. (Harry Pulliam), 1906-1979; Capehart, Homer E. (Homer Earl), 1897-1979.; Childs, Marquis W. (Marquis William), 1903-1990; Clapper, Raymond, 1892-1944.; Clardy, Kit Francis, 1892-; Connally, Tom, 1877-1963.; Corcoran, Thomas Gardiner, 1900-; Couzens, Frank, 1902-1950.; Cripps, Richard Stafford, Sir, 1889-1952.; Daniels, Jonathan, 1902-1981; Davis, Elmer Holmes, 1890-1958.; Dean, Gordon E., 1905-1958.; Diggs, Charles C.; Dingell, John D. (John David), 1894-1955.; DiSalle, Michael V. (Michael Vincent), 1908-1981; Dondero, George Anthony, 1883-1968.; Douglas, Paul H. (Paul Howard), 1892-1976; Downey, Sheridan.; Dulles, Allen Welsh, 1893-1969.; Eaton, Cyrus Stephen, 1883-; Eggleston, Arthur Francis, 1890-; Eisenhower, Milton Stover, 1899-1985; Farley, James A. (James Aloysius), 1888-1976.; Ferguson, Homer, 1889-1982.; Ford, Henry, 1917-1987.; Forrestal, James, 1892-1949.; Frear, Joseph Allen, 1903-; Fruehauf, Harvey Charles, 1893-; Fulbright, J. William (James William), 1905-1995.; Gannett, Frank E. (Frank Ernest), 1876-1957.; George, Walter F. (Walter Franklin), 1878-1957.; Green, Theodore Francis, 1867-1966.; Green, William, 1870-1952.; Griffiths, Hicks G., 1910-; Hannah, John A., 1902-1991; Harmon, Tom.; Henderson, Leon, 1895-1986; Herlong, Albert Sydney, 1909-1995; Hersey, John, 1914-1993.; Herter, Christian Archibald, 1895-1966.; Hill, Norman Llewellyn, 1895-; Hoey, Clyde Roark, 1877-1954.; Hoffman, Clare Eugene, 1875-1967.; Hoffman, Paul G. (Paul Gray), 1891-1974.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Hoover, J. Edgar (John Edgar), 1895-1972.; Hopkins, Harry L. (Harry Lloyd), 1890-1946.; Humphrey, Hubert H. (Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978.; Brown, Muriel Buck Humphrey.; Ives, Irving McNeil, 1896-1962; Johnson, Louis Arthur, 1891-1966; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973.; Johnson, Pyke.; Johnston, Eric A. (Eric Allen), 1895-1963.; Kaiser, Edgar Fosburg, 1908-; Kefauver, Estes, 1903-1963.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963.; Kerr, Robert S. (Robert Samuel), 1896-1963.; Kirchwey, Freda.; Knowland, Helen Davis Herrick.; Knowland, William F. (William Fife), 1908-1974; Knudsen, William S., 1879-1948.; Lamont, Thomas Stilwell, 1899-; Langer, William, 1886-1959.; Leahy, William D.; Lehman, Herbert H. (Herbert Henry), 1878-1963.; Lenhart, Laurence G., 1893-; Lodge, Henry Cabot, Jr., 1902-1985; Lovett, Robert A. (Robert Abercrombie), 1895-1986; Luce, Robert Harding, 1900-; McClellan, John L. (John Little), 1896-1977; McCormack, John W., 1891-1980.; McFarland, Ernest William, 1894-1984; McMahon, Brien, 1903-1952.; Mapes, Carl Herbert, 1900-; Martin, John Butlin, 1909-; Martin, Joseph William, 1884-1968.; Monroney, Mike, 1902-; Morse, Wayne L. (Wayne Lyman), 1900-1974.; Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.; Murphy, George, 1897-1961.; Murphy, Robert F., 1899-; Murray, Philip, 1886-1952.; Nelson, Donald Marr, 1888-1959.; O'Dwyer, William, 1890-1964.; Owens, Henry J.; Pastore, John O. (John Orlando), 1907-2000; Picard, Frank A., 1889-1963.; Rabaut, Louis Charles, 1886-1961.; Rankin, John Elliott, 1882-1960.; Reuther, Victor G. (Victor George), 1912-2004; Reuther, Walter, 1907-1970.; Reynolds, Quentin James, 1902-1965.; Romney, George W., 1907-1995.; Roosevelt, Dorothy Kemp, 1899?-1985.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.; Rosenberg, Anna M., 1902-; Ruml, Beardsley, 1894-1960; Russell, Richard B. (Richard Brevard), 1897-1971.; Ruthven, Alexander Grant, 1882-1971.; Saltonstall, Leverett, 1892-1979; Scholle, August, 1904-; Scripps, Edward Wyllis, 1909-; Shields, Francis J.; Sittler, Edward L.; Smith, Harold Dewey, 1898-1947.; Smith, H. Alexander (Howard Alexander), 1880-1966.; Smith, Margaret Chase, 1897-1995.; Snyder, John W. (John Wesley), 1895-1985.; Somervell, Brehon Burke, 1892-1955.; Sparkman, John, 1899-1985.; Staebler, Neil, 1905-2000; Stettinius, Edward R. (Edward Reilly), 1900-1949.; Symington, Stuart, 1901-1988; Taft, Charles P. (Charles Phelps), 1897-1983; Taft, Robert A. (Robert Alphonso), 1889-1953.; Thomas, Elbert Duncan, 1883-1953.; Tito, Josip Broz, 1892-1980.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; Van Wagoner, Murray Delos, 1898-; Voorhis, Jerry, 1901-1984; Wagner, Robert F. (Robert Ferdinand), 1877-1953.; Warren, Earl, 1891-1974.; Williams, G. Mennen, 1911-1988.; Willkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944.; Wilson, Charles Erwin, 1890-1961.; Wolcott, Jesse Paine, 1893-1969.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Airplane industry--Michigan--Willow Run.; Automobile industry--Michigan--Willow Run.; Downey, John.; Industrial buildings--Michigan--Willow Run.; Italy.; Journalism.; Kaiser-Frazer Corp.; Moody, Blair, 1902-1954.; Moody, Arthur B.; Moody family.; Political elections.; Politics and government--1946-1960.; Soldiers--American.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Williams, G. Mennen, 1911-1988.; Willow Run (Mich.)--Airplane industry.; Willow Run (Mich.)--Automobile industry.; Willow Run (Mich.)--Industrial buildings.; World War, 1939-1945.
Sound Recordings
Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969.; Elections--United States--1940.; Elections--United States--1953.; Moody, Blair, 1902-1954.; United States. Congress. House.; United States. Congress. Senate.; United States--Foreign relations--1945-1989.; United States--Politics and government--1933-1953.; United States--Politics and government--1953-1961.
Contributors - Sound Recordings
Anderson, Clinton Presba, 1895-1975; Baker, Howard Henry, 1902-1964.; Barrett, Frank Aloysius, 1892-1962.; Bender, George Harrison, 1896-1961.; Benton, William, 1900-1973.; Blatnik, John Anton, 1911-; Bolling, Richard, 1916-1991; Brown, Clarence J., 1893-1965.; Burke, Thomas A., 1898-1971.; Capehart, Homer E. (Homer Earl), 1897-1979.; Carlson, Frank, 1893-1987; Case, Francis H. (Francis Higbee), 1896-1962.; Cole, Albert M. (Albert McDonald), 1901-1994; Cole, W. Sterling (William Sterling), 1904-1987.; Cooper, John Sherman, 1901-1991; Curtis, Carl T. (Carl Thomas), 1905-2000; Dingell, John D. (John David), 1894-1955.; Douglas, Paul H. (Paul Howard), 1892-1976; Duff, James H. (James Henderson), 1883-1969.; Eberharter, Herman Peter, 1892-1958.; Farrington, Joseph R. (Joseph Rider), 1897-1954; Felix, Robert Hanna, 1904-; Flanders, Ralph E. (Ralph Edward), 1880-1970.; Frelinghuysen, Peter Hood Ballantine, 1916-; Fulbright, J. William (James William), 1905-1995.; Fulton, James G. (James Grove), 1903-1971.; Gillette, Guy Mark, 1879-1973.; Gore, Albert, 1907-1998.; Heller, John R. (John Roderick), 1905-; Hosmer, Craig, 1915-1982; Howard, Catherine.; Humphrey, Hubert H. (Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978.; Hunt, Lester Callaway, 1892-1954.; Jackson, Henry M. (Henry Martin), 1912-1983.; Javits, Jacob K. (Jacob Koppel), 1904-1986.; Jonas, Charles R. (Charles Raper), 1904-1988; Judd, Walter H., 1898-1994; Kean, Robert Winthrop, 1893-; Kefauver, Estes, 1903-1963.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963.; Kerr, Robert S. (Robert Samuel), 1896-1963.; Knowland, William F. (William Fife), 1908-1974; Langer, William, 1886-1959.; Lehman, Herbert H. (Herbert Henry), 1878-1963.; McCormack, John W., 1891-1980.; Magnuson, Warren G. (Warren Grant), 1905-1989; Mahon, George Herman, 1900-1985.; Mansfield, Mike, 1903-2001; Martin, Edward, 1879-1967.; Maybank, Burnet Rhett, 1899-1954.; Merrill, D. Bailey, 1912-; Miller, Arthur Lewis, 1892-1967.; Monroney, Mike, 1902-; Morton, Thruston B. (Thruston Ballard), 1907-1982.; Murray, James E.; Patman, Wright, 1893-1976.; Rains, Albert M. 1902-; Reece, B. Carroll (Brazilla Carroll), 1889-1961.; Richards, James P. (James Prioleau), 1894-1979; Scott, Hugh, 1900-1994; Sebrell, W. H. (William Henry), 1901-1992; Smathers, George A. (George Armistead), 1913-2007; Smith, H. Alexander (Howard Alexander), 1880-1966.; Sparkman, John, 1899-1985.; Taft, Robert A. (Robert Alphonso), 1889-1953.; Velde, Harold Himmel, 1910-1985; Vorys, John Martin, 1896-1968.; Watt, James, 1911-; Wiley, Alexander, 1884-1967.; Yorty, Samuel William, 1909-
Genre/Form:
Motion pictures.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Sound recordings.
- Biographical
  The Biographical series consists of a few folders of articles and clippings about Moody.
  - Biographical sketches, etc (Box 1)
  - Articles by or about Blair Moody (Box 1)
  - Clippings about Blair Moody, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Awards and citations (Box 1)
    (also in oversize box 29)
- Correspondence
  The Correspondence series, approximately twelve linear feet, relates primarily to the period when Moody was US Senator (1951-1952). The letters concern Senate business, arrangements for speeches and radio appearances, and letters of congratulations and thanks. Much of the correspondence prior to his appointment as Senator by Governor Williams in 1951 relates to his personal affairs, but also contains much commentary on Detroit and Michigan politics, his trips to Europe as a war correspondent and especially on economic development plans in the immediate post-war period, and of course the Washington scene.
  For the few months of his Senate appointment the bulk of Moody's papers increased markedly. Unfortunately much of it consisted of routine correspondence with constituents and others about legislation, speech requests, and invitations. Much of the incoming constituent correspondence was apparently not saved. There is considerable correspondence with G. Mennen Williams and Neil Staebler about political matters and his campaign of 1952, and with other senators about transmittal of legislation, committees, etc.
  There is very little material on the period after Moody's defeat in 1952, and very little on the campaign of 1954 except for files on Senator Charles E. Potter and his record.
  To aid the researcher, a separate index of correspondents in the Moody Collection has been compiled and is appended to this finding aid.
  - 1928-June 1941, 32 folders (Box 1)
  - July 1941-May 1946, 49 folders (Box 2)
  - June 1946-May 24, 1951, 56 folders (Box 3)
  - May 25, 1951-August 19, 1951, 35 folders (Box 4)
  - August 20, 1951-October 15, 1951, 47 folders (Box 5)
  - October 16, 1951-December 26, 1951, 63 folders (Box 6)
  - December 26, 1951-February 15, 1952, 57 folders (Box 7)
  - February 16, 1952-April 7, 1952, 51 folders (Box 8)
  - April 8, 1952-May 28, 1952, 46 folders (Box 9)
  - May 29, 1952-August 14, 1952, 60 folders (Box 10)
  - August 15, 1952-November 22, 1952, 70 folders (Box 11)
  - November 23, 1952-1954, 23 folders (Box 12)
- Personal/family
  The Personal/Family series is a small series of family correspondence and papers pertaining to family affairs.
  - Family correspondence (Box 12)
  - Divorce papers (Box 12)
  - Blair Moody, Jr. letters (Box 12)
  - Papers relating to Mother's house (payment, upkeep, etc.) (Box 12)
  - Miscellanea re. father A.B. Moody (Box 12)
- Newspaper career
  Materials relating to Moody's association with the Detroit News and Barron's Weekly have been placed in the Newspaper Career series. Included are a sampling of some of his notes as a reporter and background materials used in the preparation of stories. Part of the reference materials relate to labor strikes, notably the General Motors strike of 1945-1946.
  - Notes for articles (Box 13)
    - (Yugoslavia), 1949 (Box 13)
    - (Italy), 1949 (Box 13)
    - (Atomic seminar), Undated (Box 13)
    - (miscellaneous sampling), Undated; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Note pads, 2 portfolios (Box 13)
  - Other writings
    - Boom or Bust
      - Galley with marginal notations (Box 13)
      - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 13)
      - Correspondence with publisher, 1941 (Box 13)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
    - Edson Blair [Blair Moody] manuscripts (Box 13)
    - "Our Chin is Out" (Box 13)
  - Newspaper articles written as US Senator, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Itineraries, undated (Box 13)
  - Testimony of Blair Moody, witness in Woodward Ave. widening case, circa 1920s (Box 13)
  - Reference materials
    - Humorous clippings and writings, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous reference materials, 4 folders (Box 13)
    - Unions and strikes, undated (Box 14)
    - Unions and strikes, 1938; 8 folders (Box 14)
    - Unions and strikes, 1940 (Box 14)
    - Unions and strikes, 1941 (Box 14)
    - General Motors Strike, 1945-1946; 4 folders (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 14)
- Gridiron Club
  Moody was active in the Gridiron Club, an association of Washington correspondents. The materials Moody accumulated include skits performed, programs, correspondence about the organization, and news articles and press releases.
  - Skits
    - 1946 (Box 14)
    - 1947, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - 1948 (Box 14)
    - 1949 (Box 14)
    - 1950 (Box 14)
    - 1952, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - 1953 (Box 14)
  - Programs, seating arrangements, menus, songbooks etc
    - 1943-1944 (Box 14)
    - 1945 (Box 14)
    - 1946 (Box 14)
    - 1947 (Box 14)
    - 1948 (Box 14)
    - 1949 (Box 14)
    - 1950 (Box 14)
    - 1951 (Box 14)
    - 1952 (Box 14)
    - 1953 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence
    - 1946 (Box 15)
    - 1947 (Box 15)
    - 1948 (Box 15)
    - 1949 (Box 15)
    - 1950 (Box 15)
    - 1951 (Box 15)
    - 1952 (Box 15)
    - 1953 (Box 15)
  - News articles and press releases
    - 1946 (Box 15)
    - 1947 (Box 15)
    - 1948 (Box 15)
    - 1949 (Box 15)
    - 1950 (Box 15)
    - 1952 (Box 15)
    - 1953 (Box 15)
- Senatorial Papers
  The Senate Career series includes press releases, committee materials, and a scattering of campaign papers. As Moody was in the Senate for a brief period, the files are somewhat thin on information pertaining to current events and legislation. Though somewhat small, Moody's months in the Senate can also be documented through his scrapbook collection, his collection of speeches and transcripts of his radio/television public affairs program, and through the sound recordings of speeches and radio programs.
  - Press releases, April-October 1952; 14 folders (Box 15)
  - Letters to the editor (Box 15)
  - Press materials, Undated (Box 15)
  - Bills, resolutions, and amendments introduced by or related to Senator Moody
    - Bills and resolutions, 1951-1952; 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Bills, analyses, and amendments, undated (Box 15)
    - McClellan Bill and related material, 1950-1952 (Box 15)
    - Moody-Dingell Bill (statistical data), 1951 (Box 15)
    - Opposition to Moody-Dingell Bill (Box 15)
    - Amendments, 1951-1952; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Voting record, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Voting record (economy) (Box 15)
  - Voting record, 2 volumes (Box 15)
  - Post Office investigation
    - General, 1951 (Box 16)
    - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous, 1 portfolios (Box 16)
  - Committee on Banking and Currency, 1951-1952; 3 folders (Box 16)
  - Select Committee on Small Business
    - Weekly staff reports, 1951-1952 (Box 16)
    - Report of investigation, 1951 (Box 16)
  - Other committees (Box 16)
  - Statements made by Moody, 1951-1952; undated; 3 folders (Box 16)
  - Form responses to constituents letters, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Schedules (Box 16)
  - Campaign materials
    - 1952, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - 1954, 4 folders (Box 16)
    - Campaign poster (Box 29)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 16)
- Speeches (include radio and television appearances)
  The Speeches series date from 1940 and include both formal addresses, as well as transcripts of Moody appearances on radio and television programs. Here will be found available transcripts for Moody's Meet Your Congress program.
  - 1940 (Box 16)
  - 1941 (Box 16)
  - 1942 (Box 16)
  - 1944 (Box 16)
  - 1945 (Box 16)
  - 1946 (Box 16)
  - 1947 (Box 16)
  - 1948 (Box 16)
  - 1950 (Box 16)
  - January-March 1951 (Box 16)
  - April-June 1951 (Box 16)
  - July 1951 (Box 16)
  - August-September 1951 (Box 16)
  - October 1951 (Box 16)
  - November-December 1951 (Box 16)
  - January 1952 (Box 16)
  - February 1952, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - March 1952 (Box 16)
  - April 1952 (Box 16)
  - May 1952, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - June 1952 (Box 17)
  - July-September 1952 (Box 17)
  - October 1952 (Box 17)
  - 1951-1952, undated; 7 folders (Box 17)
  - 1953 (Box 17)
  - (radio and television), Undated; 4 folders (Box 17)
  - Meet Your Congress (radio and television program)
    - 1946 (Box 17)
    - 1947 (Box 17)
    - 1948 (Box 17)
    - 1949 (Box 17)
    - 1950 (Box 17)
    - 1951 (Box 17)
    - Undated, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Speech note cards, circa 1943-1951; 1 portfolios (Box 17)
  - Programs and notices of speeches (Box 17)
- Scrapbooks
  The Scrapbooks date from 1933 to 1951 and contain clippings of all of Moody's articles from the Detroit News and Barron's.
  - 1933-1934 (Box 18)
  - 1934-1935 (Box 18)
  - 1935-1936 (Box 18)
  - 1936-1937 (Box 18)